Watch your back.
Mean Girls is a drama, comedy film directed by Mark Waters.
Cady Heron is a hit with The Plastics, the A-list girl clique at her new school, until she makes the
mistake of falling for Aaron Samuels, the ex-boyfriend of alpha Plastic Regina George.
Cady Heron, played by Lindsay Lohan.
Regina George, played by Rachel McAdams.
Janis Ian, played by Lizzy Caplan.
Gretchen Wieners, played by Lacey Chabert.
Karen Smith, played by Amanda Seyfried.
Damian, played by Daniel Franzese.
Mean Girls is a 2004 American teen comedy film produced by Lorne Michaels
and directed by Mark Waters from a screenplay by Tina Fey.
The film stars Lindsay Lohan in the lead role, with Rachel McAdams, Tim
Meadows, Ana Gasteyer, Amy Poehler, and Fey in supporting roles.
The plot centers on Cady Heron (Lohan), a naïve teenager who transfers to an
American high school after years of homeschooling in Africa.
Cady quickly befriends outcasts Janis and Damian (Lizzy Caplan and Daniel Franzese), with the trio forming a plan to
exact revenge on Regina George (McAdams), the leader of an envied clique known as "the Plastics".
Fey conceived the idea for Mean Girls after reading Rosalind
Wiseman's 2002 self-help book Queen Bees and Wannabes.
The book describes female high school social cliques, school
bullying, and the resulting damaging effect on teenagers.
Fey also drew from her own experience at Upper Darby High School, in Upper Darby
Township, Pennsylvania, as an inspiration for some of the film's concepts.
Principal photography for Mean Girls took place
from September 2003 to November 2003.
Although the film is set in the Chicago suburb of Evanston, Illinois,
shooting took place primarily in Toronto, Ontario, Canada.
During post-production, editing was completed by Wendy Greene
Bricmont and the score was composed by Rolfe Kent.
Mean Girls premiered at the Cinerama Dome in Los Angeles on April 19, 2004, and was
theatrically released in the United States on April 30, 2004, by Paramount Pictures.
It was a box office success, grossing $130.1 million
against a production budget of $17–18 million.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised Waters' direction, Fey's script, its humor, and the performances; especially
lauded was Lohan's acting, which earned several accolades, including two MTV Movie Awards and three Teen Choice Awards.
In 2021, Lohan's performance was included in The New Yorker's list
of the best movie performances of the 21st century.
A made-for-TV sequel, Mean Girls 2, premiered on ABC Family in January 2011.
Mean Girls also spawned various adaptations, including a stage musical, which premiered on
Broadway in March 2018, with a film adaptation released in January 2024.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, illinois,
female friendship, bullying, coming of age.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.